<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Damilola Fagoyinbo Opeyemi</title>
    <description>Design.Create.Iterate</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:24:11 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:24:11 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is religious intolerance an Abrahamic construct? </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/europeana-0GuL_hVwQHA-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 550 B.C., Cyrus, king of Anshan, founded the Achaemenid Empire, he reigned from 550 B.C to 530 B.C. The Achaemenid Empire was the largest empire by the percentage of the world’s population in history. About 44% of the world’s population lived under its rule. It was also the most diverse and pluralistic empire in the world at the time, unifying different nations, tribes, languages, cultures and religions. Tolerance of varying beliefs was one of its most defining characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the height of the Roman empire, it had a conquered so many civilisations, in order to be able to control that vast empire, it needed complete cooperation from its conquered nations, it usually treated them as allies and encouraged them to participate in the glory and wealth of its empire. To all its subjects, Rome granted religious toleration with one condition attached, they must also recognize the roman deities, herein is where they had problems with the Jews, the Jews would not accept any deity outside of Yahweh. Notwithstanding, Judaism still had the status of a legal religion in the Roman Empire with formal protections. Like the Romans, almost all the conquered empires were polytheistic. Since they believed other people had their own gods, they found it relatively easy to take part in festivals celebrating Roman gods. It was simply a matter of paying respect to the Romans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 13th century, Genghis Khan consolidated the small nomadic Asian tribes into the Mongol empire and embarked on one of the greatest conquests, turning Mongolia into the largest contiguous empire in history after his death. He launched the Mongol Invasion and captured almost all of Eurasia. The Mongols were highly tolerant of most religions during the early Mongol Empire. Under his administration, all religious leaders were exempted from taxation, and from public service. Mongol emperors were known for organizing competitions of religious debates among clerics, and these would draw large audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christianity started out as a small unorganized Jewish sect that promised personal salvation after death, During the reign of Emperor Constantine the Great (A.D. 306–337), Christianity transitioned to the dominant religion in Rome. In 325, Constantine called the Council of Niceae, which was the gathering of church leaders for the foundational beliefs of orthodox Christians, the result of which is the Nicene Creed which laid out the agreed-upon beliefs of the council, and Christianity accordingly. In 380 CE, the emperor Theodosius issued the Edict of Thessalonica, which made Christianity, specifically Trinitarian Christianity (expounded by the council of Nicene), the official religion of the Roman Empire. Most other Christian sects were declared heretical, lost their legal status, and had their properties confiscated by the Roman state. Arianism and all other Christian sects were immediately condemned.The seat of the papacy was soon introduced and as the power of the pope grew, each successive pope became more efficient at getting the kings of Western Europe to do the bidding of the church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, kings who wanted to advance their empires would declare they had converted and would request an army from the pope in order to conquer and convert neighbouring people. Notable amongst them is the consolidation of Celtic tribes into one Frankish kingdom who would be known today as the French. Missionary, conquest and enforcement saw the spread of Christianity across Europe and around the world. The crusades, the Spanish inquisition started out as tools for defence and regulation of the faith. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Inquisition&quot;&gt;The Inquisition was originally intended primarily to identify heretics among those who converted from Judaism and Islam to Catholicism, the regulation of the faith of newly converted Catholics was intensified after the royal decrees issued in 1492 and 1502 ordering Jews and Muslims to convert to Catholicism or leave Castile&lt;/a&gt;. In colonial Massachusetts, a wave of mass hysteria triggered the Salem witch trials where 19 “witches” were hanged. Jesus had instructed his disciples to love their enemies, but after Emperor Constantine had turned to Christianity, with the full financial support and army of the Roman empire, Christians acquired the opportunity to use violence toward competing groups and pagans, even though they were instructed to love them personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 7th Century, Angel Gabriel visited an Orphan named Mohammed ibn Abdullah (PBUH) in a Cave in Mecca, calling for submission to the one God, the expectation of the imminent Last Judgement, and taking care for the poor and needy. This message soon resonated with the Arab but was met with resistance from the Nobles in Mecca. The trade of the Notables of Mecca at the time relied on the sale of polytheist merchandise, which explains the reason for the resistance. In 622, he fled to Medina for fear of his life and gained a massive following. With this newfound Muslim base, Mohammed (PBUH) launched a series of raids on Meccan caravans. Mohammed (PBUH) was a military genius and soon led the defeat of the Meccans in a war of 1000 Meccans vs 313 Muslim troops in the Battle of Badr (624 CE). After the battle at Badr, the Muslims became a military force to be reckoned with. They launched a series of wars with competing Abrahamic Religions and pagans alike and soon enough, the gates of Mecca, which they have once fled became open to them. With Mecca in the hands of the Muslims, Mohammed (PBUH) offered an amnesty to all those who surrendered and accepted Islam. The story of wars and conquest continued with Islam expanding as several Islamic caliphates were formed across Asia and Europe. The 8th century brought about the Islamic golden age, which gave rise to many authorities in polymaths, mathematics, astronomy, philosophy and medicine. Spain was also captured. The 13th century saw the rise and fall of many Islamic caliphates, the loss of Spain in the Reconquista and many others. They also suffered many losses from the Mongol Invasions until the age of the Islamic Gunpowder ushered in the Ottoman Empire.The 19th and 20th century saw the fall of the Islamic world to the European world powers. Till this days the rivalry between the two dominant religions continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In West Africa, asides ethnic and regional conflicts, religious conflicts were unheard of, and the religious tolerance permitted many Africans to allow their children to convert to the new religion when the Christian missionaries came. Agreed, this can be debated as there are not many records documented about what transpired at the time, but from tales passed down, it can be observed that many of our ancestors were tolerant enough to allow their children to adopt the religion of the West. The same courtesy, unfortunately, is not extended by the offspring of these same once tolerant ancestors; fire and brimstone will be raised if a child from a Christian home desires to adopt Islam or vice versa. With the acceptance of Western religion came the deliberate destruction of places of worship of many indigenous African religions, a gesture which if reciprocated will have the Abrahamic religion screaming ‘persecution’. There has been continuous stigmatization and oppression of the indigenous African religion as well as the demonization and demeaning of everything around their practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be completely dishonest of me to conclude this piece without mentioning religious intolerance outside of the Abrahamic religions. China has continuously carried out repression action against the Uighurs, a huge population of which are Muslims, in Xinjiang, and detained them in reeducation camps, although they have consistently maintained that they are not infringing on their human rights. There have also been four Buddhist persecution events that have occurred in China, historically. Depending on where you stand, it could be argued that the actions of the Chinese are purely political and not religious, I’ll leave that to the audience to ponder on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering the fact that the most iconic historic figure and civilization at their peak allowed religious freedom for their subjects as highlighted in the varying paragraphs above, one cannot help but wonder if religious intolerance at scale is a construct of Abrahamic religions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constitutional Rights Foundation* (2020). Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crf-usa.org/bill-of-rights-in-action/bria-13-4-b-religious-tolerance-and-persecution-in-the-roman-empire&quot;&gt;https://www.crf-usa.org/bill-of-rights-in-action/bria-13-4-b-religious-tolerance-and-persecution-in-the-roman-empire&lt;/a&gt; (Accessed: 15 May 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What ancient Egypt tells us about a world without religious conflict&lt;/em&gt; (2015). Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2015/oct/30/ancient-egypt-faith-after-the-pharaohs&quot;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2015/oct/30/ancient-egypt-faith-after-the-pharaohs&lt;/a&gt; (Accessed: 15 May 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christianity in the Roman Empire (article) / Khan Academy&lt;/em&gt; (2020). Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khanacademy.org/humanities/world-history/ancient-medieval/christianity/a/roman-culture&quot;&gt;https://www.khanacademy.org/humanities/world-history/ancient-medieval/christianity/a/roman-culture&lt;/a&gt; (Accessed: 17 May 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Genghis Khan&lt;/em&gt; (2017). Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genghis_Khan&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genghis_Khan&lt;/a&gt; (Accessed: 17 May 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Religion in the Mongol Empire&lt;/em&gt; (2016). Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religion_in_the_Mongol_Empire&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religion_in_the_Mongol_Empire&lt;/a&gt; (Accessed: 17 May 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Greek religion&lt;/em&gt; (2020). Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_Greek_religion&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_Greek_religion&lt;/a&gt; (Accessed: 17 May 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;History of Christianity&lt;/em&gt; (2020). Available at: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_Christianity#Early_Christianity_(c._31/33%E2%80%93324) (Accessed: 17 May 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arianism&lt;/em&gt; (2020). Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arianism&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arianism&lt;/a&gt;(Accessed: 17 May 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christianity in Europe: History, Spread and Decline (2020). Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://study.com/academy/lesson/christianity-in-europe-history-spread-decline.html&quot;&gt;https://study.com/academy/lesson/christianity-in-europe-history-spread-decline.html&lt;/a&gt; (Accessed: 17 May 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.historyworld.net/wrldhis/PlainTextHistories.asp?ParagraphID=etn&quot;&gt;http://www.historyworld.net/wrldhis/PlainTextHistories.asp?ParagraphID=etn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discoverfrance.net/France/History/DF_history.shtml&quot;&gt;https://www.discoverfrance.net/France/History/DF_history.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Inquisition&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Inquisition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/religion/islam&quot;&gt;https://www.history.com/topics/religion/islam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_Islam&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_Islam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ancient.eu/islam/&quot;&gt;https://www.ancient.eu/islam/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salem_witch_trials&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salem_witch_trials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Albert, C.G &amp;amp; Riemer, R 2014, Violence in Ancient Christianity: Victims and Perpetrators, Brill Academic Publishers, The Netherlands.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;China’s Repression of Uighurs in Xinjiang&lt;/em&gt; (2020). Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/backgrounder/chinas-repression-uighurs-xinjiang&quot;&gt;https://www.cfr.org/backgrounder/chinas-repression-uighurs-xinjiang&lt;/a&gt; (Accessed: 11 August 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Four Buddhist Persecutions in China&lt;/em&gt; (2020). Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Buddhist_Persecutions_in_China#:~:text=The%20Old%20History%20of%20the,of%20China's%206%2C030%20Buddhist%20temples.&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Buddhist_Persecutions_in_China#:~:text=The%20Old%20History%20of%20the,of%20China’s%206%2C030%20Buddhist%20temples&lt;/a&gt;. (Accessed: 11 August 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 23:29:52 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/Is-religious-intolerance-an-Abrahamic-construct/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/Is-religious-intolerance-an-Abrahamic-construct/</guid>
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
        <category>religion</category>
        
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
        <category>religion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Storytelling: leveraging on one of humans basic emotional trigger </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mike-erskine-S_VbdMTsdiA-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@mikejerskine?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Mike Erskine&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/storytelling?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;The statue was erected in the village square. It was done under the cover of darkness and the sculptor remained as mysterious as the subject.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The villagers spoke among themselves and speculated. What did it mean? Who had created it? It could have come from anyone, but who was less important. Wondering what became a pastime. Before long the statue and the stories became part of their way of life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One day a scream tore through the town. The statue was gone without a clue as to how or why it had disappeared. All that was left were the stories.&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fairytalefeminista.wordpress.com/2019/01/29/100-word-challenge/&quot;&gt;Storied by Ivia Cruz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One often underlooked art in communicating concepts, ideas and information is storytelling. It is one of the earliest forms of cultural, knowledge and information exchange. Through storytelling, we developed myths, legends, we socialized and passed down knowledge. In fact, Storytelling is the fundamental principle in which our entire religious beliefs are built on. It is impossible to talk about the evolution of culture without discussing storytelling. Whenever humans hear or read stories, it evokes some primal instinct in them that reminds them of their ancestral primitive past. Stories capture our imaginations. And for the most part, have helped us preserve historical records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Zipes Jack noted in the book, The irresistible Fairy Tale: “Stories may not actually breathe, but they can animate”. Stories animate human life; that is their work. Stories work with people, for people, and always stories work on people, affecting what people are able to see as real, as possible, and as worth doing or best avoided (Arthur Frank, 2010). For a long time, before we started to study the world around us, we tried to understand ourselves and our world through storytelling. Hence it remains one of the most effective means of communication, an ability that has given us a superior edge compared to our primate relatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, there is a reason why misinformation spreads more than factual information. It’s because misinformation capitalizes on previously held biases, factual information, on the other hand, is most times, boring and plagued with too much detailed information, with too much detail than is actually necessary. Generally, people are impressed by how much information you know but are inspired by your narration and relatability of the information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the 5G conspiracy, conspiracy theorists employed storytelling to spread misinformation, most times appealing to previously held religious biases and consumer anxiety, employing tales of doom and apocalypse that is found in the major religious texts. I watched in awe as people tried to counter conspiracy theorists with facts, talking about microwave spectrums, radiofrequency radiation, ionizing and non-ionizing radio waves. Even as someone with an engineering background, such terms remind me of my not exactly pleasant science classes and find them boring. Imagine the average Joe who probably hasn’t sat down in a science class his whole life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans evolved all kinds of folklore and fairy tales with heroes and villains, knights in shining armour and damsel in distress and this has been shared repeatedly. For most people, they will live a flatline and not eventful life, there is a constant need to live the eventful and heroic life we have come to know and enjoy, hence any narrative that puts us in that light is embraced. We also empathised with other people who have had experiences similar to ours, humans by nature are emotional beings. The ones that obsess with power and success understand this and have used it as a tool of power and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Goodluck Ebele Jonathan won the sympathy of Nigerians without any real manifesto. He told them “I had no shoes, if I can make it, you can make it” That was almost the entirety of his campaign. In the 2016 America election, Donald Trump based his entire campaign on the motto “Make America Great Again”. He Created a scenario where immigrants were the Enemy and Americans were the heroes, I watched some of his debates against his most prominent opponent, while she tried to explain her policies, Donald Trump reduced them to simple concepts that were easily comprehensive to the average Americans, “You want to kill babes!”, “We need the wall”, “bring back our jobs”. There are 2 concepts DT employed, He used the hero-villain narrative at every point in the election campaign period, He also always used simplicity when describing his manifesto, His opponent, on the other hand, was too detailed, too much experience might be a disadvantage in communicating ideas some times. In the 1940s, millions of Germans looked on as Adolf Hitler ended the lives of so many innocent jews. With his amazing talent for rhetoric and his crafty use of propaganda, Hitler was able to convince people that the Jews were responsible for their economic retrogression and their loss in the first world war. He waged war on the enemy, a classic case of hero vs villain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses almost always employ this classic fairytale theme to win the hearts of consumers. It’s always common to see company founders sold as people coming from humble backgrounds, the popular underdog story, or popular companies selling the hero vs villain narrative against their competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2003, a Stanford dropout named Elizabeth Holmes, great-great-granddaughter to Charles Fleischmann, founded a startup called Theranos, it was building a blood analyser technology that could run thousands of tests just from a single prick of blood, from the comfort of your home. The company earned over $600 million in funding and was valued at $9 billion. Theranos achieved all this feat without exactly having the product they advertised, investors were completely swayed with the underdog story who was going to take on the big Pharma, a 19-year-old knight in shining armour who was going to slay the Big Pharma dragon, Elizabeth Holmes, armed with persuasive skills sold her story with amazing efficiency, everyone wanted a piece in the big pie and no one wanted to be left behind. There were three plots at play here, Charles Fleischmann had built a yeast empire and amassed so much wealth, but the wealth had vanished with successive generations, Elizabeth was seen as the person to restore the empire; The popular Silicon valley college dropout folklore; And an underdog who was fighting the Big Pharma like Steve Jobs had taken on IBM decades before. In her talks, she would tell tales that evoked emotional responses. Unfortunately, in this tale, the Knight was consumed in one big swallow. In 2017, allegations of fraud, lying to investors, lying about financial projections and many more allegations started the decline of Theranos, the company went from 9 billion to zero in a whim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storytelling can be used to evoke human emotional responses, this can be used to inform, control, persuade and manipulate, like everything in the possession of man, it can be used for social good or to wreak havoc, as long as humans exist, we will have people armed with the skill to evoke both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ZIPES, J. (2012). &lt;em&gt;The irresistible fairy tale: the cultural and social history of a genre&lt;/em&gt;. Princeton, N.J., Princeton University Press&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;100 Word Challenge&lt;/em&gt; (2019). Available at: https://fairytalefeminista.wordpress.com/2019/01/29/100-word-challenge/ (Accessed: 30 July 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why did Hitler hate the Jews?&lt;/em&gt; (2018). Available at: https://www.annefrank.org/en/anne-frank/go-in-depth/why-did-hitler-hate-jews/ (Accessed: 30 July 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 08:29:52 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/Storytelling-leveraging-on-one-of-humans-basic-emotional-trigger/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/Storytelling-leveraging-on-one-of-humans-basic-emotional-trigger/</guid>
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I am Ope</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, This is obviously my first post, the thought of having my personal blog has bounced on and off a few times, but I’d been too lazy to set up one, or maybe I get easily carried away by happenings around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my commitment this year is to take knowldge sharing seriously and as such open myself to learning new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be using this platform to share insights, ideas, discoveries and my thoughts, as I am using static templating tool for generating the blog template, there is no room for leaving comments, always feel free to reachout to me on any of my social media handles ( preferably on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/ope_fago&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; ) in case of errors, typos or if you’ve got a few points to add to what I say here, honestly, I don’t bite and i am particular opened to criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very much happy to start out this journey and hope it will be one that will last a lifetime, looking forward to sharing and learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:::Update:::&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; After some tweaking, i finally figured how to add comments and creating extensions using &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/&quot;&gt;disqus&lt;/a&gt; plugin, I didn’t mention that this blog is set up using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, which is an awesome blogging framework for those who love to tinker&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 15:29:52 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/Hi-I-am-Ope/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/Hi-I-am-Ope/</guid>
        
        <category>about</category>
        
        <category>introduction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
